<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Least Authority Blog</title><link>https://leastauthority.com/blog/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/feeds/jessica-augustus-and-inkblotest.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reset The Net with the Upgraded Simple Secure Storage Service</title><link>https://leastauthority.com/blog/least_authority_releases_s4+_as_part_of_reset_the_net.html</link><description>&lt;!-- -*- coding: utf-8-with-signature-unix; fill-column: 73; indent-tabs-mode: nil -*- --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.resetthenet.org/"&gt;“Reset The Net!”&lt;/a&gt; is a broad coalition of many businesses, organizations, and individuals. We're empowering people to protect themselves on the Internet by using end-to-end encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Least Authority is &lt;a class="reference external" href="/about_us"&gt;a team of computer security professionals&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to providing &lt;em&gt;freedom-compatible&lt;/em&gt; storage. For us that means end-to-end-encryption and Free and Open Source code. Always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In support of “Reset The Net!” we have upgraded our Secure Simple Storage Service (S4), reduced the price by 50%, and included &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; personal data storage in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S4 uses the Least Authority File System, a technology designed with
user security in mind, and built from the ground up to provide that security as well as we know how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such tools allow the user to store data on the Internet without any third party (even us!) breaching the confidentiality or integrity of the data. This keeps the power where it belongs, in the hands of the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce S4 as a command-line utility, and we are presently developing a Dropbox-esque friendly file-syncing utility named “Magic Folders”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're comfortable with the command line, you can take part now with a free 30-day trial and continued service at half the previous price.
By using Least Authority's secure cloud storage service, you're becoming a supporter of the further development of the Free and Open Source crypto system,
and you're getting a great tool right now for your own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video demonstrates its use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/kLrcsyHqrwQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does that look like the product for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/s4-subscription-form" class="btn btn-danger btn-large signup-button"&gt;Sign up for S4!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not familiar with the command line? Don't worry we have a product in the works for you! Give us your email and we'll let you know when Magic Folders is ready!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="/collect-email" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" class="big-signup-form signup-form form-inline"&gt;
   &lt;input type="email" name="Email" placeholder="Email address" required="true"&gt;
   &lt;input type="hidden" name="ProductName" value="magicfolder"&gt;
   &lt;input type="hidden" name="ProductFullName" value="Magic Folder"&gt;
   &lt;button type="submit" class="btn btn-danger btn-large signup-button"&gt;I'm interested!&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jessica Augustus and Inkblotest</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:leastauthority.com,2014-06-05:blog/least_authority_releases_s4+_as_part_of_reset_the_net.html</guid><category>cloud</category><category>s4</category></item></channel></rss>