<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Least Authority Blog</title><link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/feeds/news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://leastauthority.com/blog/</id><updated>2014-06-01T12:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Reset The Net with Least Authority</title><link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/least_authority_releases_s4+_as_part_of_reset_the_net.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-01T12:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Jessica Augustus and Inkblotest</name></author><id>tag:https://leastauthority.com/blog,2014-06-01:least_authority_releases_s4+_as_part_of_reset_the_net.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- -*- coding: utf-8-with-signature-unix; fill-column: 73; indent-tabs-mode: nil -*- --&gt;
&lt;!-- XXX insert "Reset The Net!" logo, name, banner, hyperlink here, before the description of Least Authority --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Least Authority is &lt;a class="reference external" href="/about_us"&gt;a globally distributed company&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to providing User controlled, verifiably secure storage. For us that means end-to-end-encryption and Free and Open Source code. Always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.resetthenet.org/"&gt;Reset The Net&lt;/a&gt; we have upgraded our Secure Simple Storage Service (S4), reduced the price by 50%, and now include &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; personal data storage in the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S4 uses the Least Authority File System, a technology designed with
User security in mind, and built from the ground up to provide that security as well as we know how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such tools allow the User to store data on the Internet without any third party (even us!) breaching the confidentiality or integrity of the data. This keeps the power where it belongs, in the hands of the User.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce S4 as a command-line utility, and we are presently developing a Dropbox-esque friendly file-syncing utility named “Magic Folders”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're comfortable with the command line, you can take part now with a free 30-day trial and continued service at half the previous price.
By using Least Authority's secure cloud storage service, you're becoming a supporter of the further development of the Free and Open Source crypto system,
and you're getting a great tool right now for your own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kLrcsyHqrwQ"&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates its use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/s4-subscription-form" class="btn btn-danger btn-large signup-button"&gt;Sign up!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not familiar with the command line?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry we have a product in the works for you! Give us your email and we'll let you know when Magic Folders is ready!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="/collect-email" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" class="big-signup-form signup-form form-inline"&gt;
   &lt;input type="email" name="Email" placeholder="Email address" required="true"&gt;
   &lt;input type="hidden" name="ProductName" value="magicfolder"&gt;
   &lt;input type="hidden" name="ProductFullName" value="Magic Folder"&gt;
   &lt;button type="submit" class="btn btn-danger btn-large signup-button"&gt;Sign up!&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</summary><category term="cloud"></category><category term="s4"></category></entry><entry><title>Least Authority Performs Security Audit For Cryptocat</title><link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/least_authority_performs_security_audit_for_cryptocat.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-02T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zooko Wilcox-O'Hearn</name></author><id>tag:https://leastauthority.com/blog,2014-04-02:least_authority_performs_security_audit_for_cryptocat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- -*- coding: utf-8-with-signature-unix; fill-column: 73; indent-tabs-mode: nil -*- --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second post in our series about security audits of Free and
Open Source end-to-end encryption software. The first post in the series
was about our security audit of SpiderOak's &lt;a class="reference external" href="/blog/least_authority_performs_security_audit_for_spideroak.html"&gt;crypton&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://leastauthority.com/about_us"&gt;Our mission&lt;/a&gt; at LeastAuthority is to bring verifiable end-to-end
security to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of that mission, in addition to operating the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://leastauthority.com/product_s4"&gt;S4&lt;/a&gt; simple secure
storage service, we also perform security consulting. We
LeastAuthoritarians have extensive experience in security and
cryptography, and other companies sometimes ask us to analyze the
security of their protocols and software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We audited the widely-used &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://crypto.cat/"&gt;Cryptocat&lt;/a&gt; encrypted chat program. This
audit was funded by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.opentechfund.org/"&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/a&gt; as part of their &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.opentechfund.org/labs#redteam"&gt;Red Team&lt;/a&gt;
project to provide multiple professional security audits to Internet
freedom projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-were-the-results"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What were the results?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found several security issues in the version of Cryptocat that we
examined (Cryptocat v2.1.15). For each one, we reported it to the
Cryptocat developers, and they have either deployed a fix in a newer
release of Cryptocat or else disabled the feature that has the
vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete list of the issues we found is at the end of this article,
along with a link to the report document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we didn't have time to examine all parts of Cryptocat that
we wanted to. We concentrated on the “crypto-related” parts: key
generation and key management, random number generation, encryption and
decryption, authentication and integrity, and the new file transfer
feature. Most of the issues that we found were in those areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our report explains what parts of it we looked at most closely (this is
called the &amp;quot;coverage&amp;quot; results of the audit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="parting-thoughts"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;parting thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank the Cryptocat project, led by Nadim Kobeissi, for
their commitment to doing development in the open, inviting external
review, and moving to address the issues we uncovered. This open
development process is a good complement to Cryptocat's Free and Open
Source publication of their code and their commitment to providing
end-to-end security for their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I'd like to thank Cryptocat for their unflagging focus on
&lt;em&gt;usability&lt;/em&gt;. Usability is a critical factor if we are going to succeed at
bringing verifiable end-to-end security to everyone, and it is an area
where we as a community and as a society need to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="any-questions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Any questions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these results or the process, please
contact us or the Cryptocat developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next project we are auditing is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://globaleaks.org/"&gt;GlobaLeaks&lt;/a&gt;, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="further-reading"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;further reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full report: &lt;a class="reference external" href="/static/publications/LeastAuthority-Cryptocat-audit-report.pdf"&gt;Report of Security Audit of Cryptocat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.crypto.cat/2014/04/recent-audits-and-coming-improvements/"&gt;post on the Cryptocat blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the Cryptocat github issue tracker to track the status of each issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/575"&gt;Issue A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/576"&gt;Issue B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/577"&gt;Issue C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/578"&gt;Issue D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/606"&gt;Issue E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/607"&gt;Issue F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cryptocat/cryptocat/issues/608"&gt;Issue G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="consultancy"></category><category term="cryptocat"></category></entry><entry><title>Least Authority Performs Security Audit For SpiderOak</title><link href="https://leastauthority.com/blog/least_authority_performs_security_audit_for_spideroak.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-20T13:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Zooko Wilcox-O'Hearn</name></author><id>tag:https://leastauthority.com/blog,2014-02-20:least_authority_performs_security_audit_for_spideroak.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- -*- coding: utf-8-with-signature-unix; fill-column: 73; indent-tabs-mode: nil -*- --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://leastauthority.com/about_us"&gt;Our mission&lt;/a&gt; at LeastAuthority is to bring verifiable end-to-end
security to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of that mission, in addition to operating the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://leastauthority.com/product_s4"&gt;S4&lt;/a&gt; simple secure
storage service, we also run a security consulting business. We
LeastAuthoritarians have extensive experience in security and
cryptography, and other companies pay us to analyze the security of their
protocols and software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all of our consulting clients are making Free and Open Source
software which protects user freedoms and works against censorship. It is
wonderful that in this day and age we can get paid to work on software in
the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our clients is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://spideroak.com/"&gt;SpiderOak&lt;/a&gt;, a company who, like LeastAuthority,
sells cloud storage with end-to-end encryption. They didn't hire us to
evaluate the security of their current storage product (that would be a
big job!), but instead to do a limited, two-week long, security audit of
their new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://crypton.io/"&gt;Crypton.io&lt;/a&gt; framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a fun project because we got to learn some of the details of the
&lt;cite&gt;Crypton.io&lt;/cite&gt; design and implementation. We came away with a favorable
impression of the professionalism and good engineering practices of the
SpiderOak team. &lt;cite&gt;Crypton.io&lt;/cite&gt; is all Free and Open Source software, and it
is designed for real, end-to-end security, which is part of why we wanted
to take the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today SpiderOak &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://spideroak.com/blog/20140220090004-responsibly-bringing-new-cryptography-product-market"&gt;has published the security auditing report&lt;/a&gt;. We'd like
to thank them for producing &lt;cite&gt;Crypton.io&lt;/cite&gt;, subjecting it to this kind of
independent review, and publishing the complete results. That's the right
way to do things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next security audit that we performed, was for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://crypto.cat/"&gt;Cryptocat&lt;/a&gt;
secure chat app. We expect the report from that to also be published
soon. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cloud"></category><category term="lafs"></category><category term="s4"></category><category term="consultancy"></category><category term="spideroak"></category><category term="crypton"></category><category term="cryptocat"></category></entry></feed>